<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
  <string-array name="locations_en">
    <item>Green Space 1|A perfect green space to start and end the walk|This green space has several interesting trees and plants around. We selected this space because there’s seating available and there are rest rooms close by as well, so it’s ideal to take a break after or before the walk.|https://treewalks.github.io//2022/12/01/green_space_1_en.html||</item>
    <item>Thread palm|Evergreen, native to northern Mexico, drought tolerant|Evergreen. Native to northern Mexico. Slender, tapering trunk. Fan-shaped, deeply lobed leaves. Light pink flowers in long inflorescences produce copious quantities of seeds. Drought tolerant.|https://treewalks.github.io//2022/12/02/thread_palm_en.html|Can grow up to 80\'-100\'. Notably, these are the palm species that tower over L.A.|Northern Mexico</item>
    <item>Green Space 2|A green space at the heart of Agricultural Sciences|This is another cool green space with interesting plants and trees surrounded by the Agricultural Sciences Building. The building has also several plated planted specimen around it.|https://treewalks.github.io//2022/12/03/green_space_2_en.html||</item>
    <item>Horsetail tree|Long, thin, green branchlets resemble pine needles|Native to eastern Australia and Pacific islands. Long, thin, green branchlets resemble pine needles. True leaves are inconspicuous and scalelike. Fruit is a small, woody cone. Drought tolerant.|https://treewalks.github.io//2022/12/04/horsetail_tree_en.html|In South/South East Asia, names of people and places are derived from this tree, such as Casuarina Beach|Eastern Australia and Pacific islands</item>
    <item>Common fig|Large shrub or small tree. Drought tolerant when established.|Deciduous. Native to the eastern Mediterranean region. Large shrub or small tree. Trunk and branches become gnarled with age. Large, rounded leaves have 3 or 5 deep lobes. Edible fruit is ripe in summer. Drought tolerant when established.|https://treewalks.github.io//2022/12/05/common_fig_en.html|Figs were one of the first plants cultivated by humans, with fossils of figs being found in Gilgal I, an early neolithic village|Eastern Mediterranean region</item>
    <item>Afghan pine|Native to Russia, Afghanistan and Pakistan. Drought tolerant.|Evergreen. Native from southern Russia to Pakistan. Conical to mounded growth habit. Dark green needles, 5”-6” long, in bundles of two. Drought tolerant.|https://treewalks.github.io//2022/12/06/afghan_pine_en.html|Afghan pines naturally grow in 20" of annual rainfall, so overwatering them is dangerous to the health of the tree|Southern Russia to Pakistan</item>
    <item>Canary Island pine|Native to the Canary Islands. Drought tolerant.|Evergreen. Native to the Canary Islands. Upright, conical growth habit. Drooping branchlets of deep green needles, 9”-12” long, in bundles of three. Drought tolerant.|https://treewalks.github.io//2022/12/07/canary_island_pine_en.html|Due to its adaptations, it is one of the most fire-resistant conifers in the world|Canary Islands</item>
    <item>Peppermint gum|Evergreen. Native to Australia. Drought tolerant.|Evergreen. Native to Australia. Upright main trunk, rounded crown, spreading branches. Reddish brown bark. Narrow, light green, peppermint-scented leaves. Drought tolerant.|https://treewalks.github.io//2022/12/08/peppermint_gum_en.html|Not a fun fact, but this tree happens to be toxic to cats, dogs, and weirdly, horses|Australia</item>
    <item>Aristocrat pear|Decidous. Species is native to China and Korea. Drought tolerant when established.|Deciduous. Species is native to China and Korea. Cultivar was selected by W.T. Shaw, Independence, Kentucky. Broadly conical growth habit. Oval, dark green leaves have wavy margins. Red fall color. White flowers in umbel-like racemes, present in March. Drought tolerant when established.|https://treewalks.github.io//2022/12/09/aristocrat_pear_en.html|Unfun fact - it is considered an invasive species in the East and Midwest. Spreads only if different cultivars can be cross-pollinated|China and Korea</item>
    <item>Cork oak|Evergreen. Native to the western Mediterranean region. Drought tolerant.|Evergreen. Native to the western Mediterranean region. Trunk is covered with thick, corky bark. Dull green, toothed leaves. Drought tolerant.|https://treewalks.github.io//2022/12/10/cork_oak_en.html|Cork is harvested from these trees, by removing the outer layer of bark, produced by the cork cambium|Western Mediterranean region</item>
    <item>Allergy-free garden|Allergy-Free demonstration garden by the Arboretum at CSU Fresno|This large area demonstration garden coontains several areas and many placated species such as:
<ul><li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Viburnum_tinus">Larustinus Viburnum tinus</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.monrovia.com/pink-princess-escallonia.html">Escallonia Exoniensis Fradesii</a> <a href="https://www.tynursery.com/plant-library/woody-ornamentals/escallonia-x-exoniensis-fradesii/">Escallonia</a></li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Calycanthus_occidentalis">Spice Bush (Calycanthus occidentalis)</a> by the Rotary Club of Fresno</li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Buxus_microphylla">Chinese Boxwood</a> (<a href="https://www.gardenia.net/plant/buxus-microphylla-var-japonica-green-beauty">Buxus microphylla japonica</a>)</li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heuchera_sanguinea">Coral Bells (Heuchera sanguinea)</a></li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Symphoricarpos_albus">Snowberry (Symphoricarpos albus)</a> by the Rotary Club of Fresno</li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arbutus_unedo">Strawberry tree (Arbutus unedo)</a> by the Rotary Club of Fresno</li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lycianthes_rantonnetii">Blue Potato Bush (Lycianthes rantonnetii ‘Royal Robe’)</a> by the Rotary Club of Fresno</li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chaenomeles">Flowering Quince (Chaenomeles)</a> by the Rotary Club of Fresno</li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baccharis_pilularis">Coyote Bush (Baccharis pilularis ‘Pigeon Point’)</a> by the Rotary Club of Fresno</li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ophiopogon_japonicus">Mondo Grass (Ophiopogon japonicus)</a> by the Rotary Club of Fresno</li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leptospermum">Leptospermum (Leptospermum ‘Dark Shadows’)</a> by the Rotary Club of Fresno</li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alocasia">Elephant Ear (Alocasia ‘Portora’)</a> by the Rotary Club of Fresno</li>
</ul>|https://treewalks.github.io//2022/12/11/allergy_free_garden_en.html|Encompasses acre and over 50 non-allergenic trees and shrubs. Significant donations from the Rotary Club of Fresno.|</item>
    <item>Jelly palm|Evergreen. Native to South America. Drought tolerant.|Evergreen. Native to South America. Thick-trunked. Arching, feathery, gray-green fronds curve downward toward the trunk. Long panicles of yellow flowers. Orange, edible fruit. Drought tolerant.|https://treewalks.github.io//2022/12/12/jelly_palm_en.html|Fruits from this palm are edible and nutritious and are used to make juices, liquors, jelly, and ice cream|South America</item>
    <item>Hemp tree|Deciduous. Native from southern Europe to western Asia. Drought tolerant.|Deciduous. Native from southern Europe to western Asia. Shrub-like, often multi-trunked tree. Open, spreading habit. Dark green, palmate leaves have 5-7 leaflets. Upright, terminal panicles of small, lavender-blue flowers in summer and sometimes again in autumn. Drought tolerant.|https://treewalks.github.io//2022/12/13/hemp_tree_en.html|This tree was considered to be sacred towards Hestia/Vesta, the Greek/Roman goddess of the hearth|Southern Europe to Western Asia</item>
    <item>Tree garden|Garden of mostly drought resistant and / or California native trees.|This lovely tree garden South of Concert Hall contains numerous drought tolerant and / or California native trees, such as:
<ul><li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Triadica_sebifera">Sapium sebiferum</a>, <a href="https://www.csustan.edu/campus-tree-story-map/chinese-tallow-triadica-sebifera">Chinese tallow tree, popcorn tree</a>. Height: 35’, Width: 35’, Deciduous. Native to China. Effect of foliage is open rather than dense. Poplar-like leaves turn red-orange in fall. Spikes of tiny, yellow flowers in spring. Brown fruit capsules open to reveal white, waxy seeds that persist on the tree in winter. Deeply rooted. Drought tolerant.</li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quercus_lobata">Quercus lobata</a>, <a href="https://www.csustan.edu/campus-tree-story-map/valley-oak-quercus-lobate">valley oak, California white oak</a>. Height: 70’, Width: 70’, Deciduous. Native to California’s interior valleys, coast ranges, and Sierra Nevada foothills. Spreading growth habit. Trunk and limbs have gray, checked bark. Leaves are deeply lobed. Fruit is an edible acorn.</li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cupressus_macrocarpa">Cupressus macrocarpa</a>, <a href="https://plants.ces.ncsu.edu/plants/hesperocyparis-macrocarpa/">Monterey Cypress</a>. Height: 40’, Evergreen. Native to Monterey County, California. Short life span in the valley. Pyramidal growth habit when young, spreading when mature.</li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lagerstroemia_indica">Lagerstroemia indica</a>, <a href="https://www.csustan.edu/campus-tree-story-map/crape-myrtle-lagerstroemia-indica">crape myrtle</a>. Height: 6-30’, Deciduous. Native to China. Large shrub or small tree, can be multi-trunked. Bark flakes off, leaving smooth, pale trunk and branches. Red-orange fall color. Large terminal panicles of white, pink or lavender flowers, depending on the cultivar, from June to September. Drought tolerant.</li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quercus_agrifolia">Quercus agrifolia</a>, <a href="https://www.csustan.edu/campus-tree-story-map/coast-live-oak">coast live oak, California live oak</a>. Height: 30-75’, Width: 60-100’, Evergreen. Native to California’s coast ranges. Spreading growth habit. Rounded, toothed, dark green leaves. Drought tolerant when established.</li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pinus_sabiniana">Pinus sabiniana</a>, <a href="https://www.csustan.edu/campus-tree-story-map/gray-pine-pinus-sabiniana">foothill pine, gray pine</a>. Height: 40-80’, Width: 30’ Evergreen. Native to California’s coast ranges and Sierra Nevada (elevation 100’-3,000’). Upright, with open growth habit. Can have multiple trunks. Needles in bundles of three. Large cones contain edible seeds. Drought tolerant.</li>
</ul>|https://treewalks.github.io//2022/12/14/tree_garden_en.html||</item>
    <item>Italian cypress|Native to the eastern Mediterranean region and western Asia. Drought tolerant.|Evergreen. Native to the eastern Mediterranean region and western Asia. Upright, narrowly columnar growth habit. Dark green foliage. Drought tolerant.|https://treewalks.github.io//2022/12/15/italian_cypress_en.html|The cypress was culturally connected to death and the underworld in Greek and Roman cultures, and mourning in modern religion|Eastern Mediterranean region and Western Asia</item>
    <item>Incense cedar|Evergreen. Native to Western North America. Drought tolerant.|The Reflective Pathway is a beautiful garden next to the fountain and the University Restaurant features numerous trees and plants. One of them is the incense cedar: Evergreen. Native to Western North America (Oregon to Baja California). Columnar growth habit with conical crown Cinnamon-brown trunk. Dark green foliage is aromatic when crushed. Drought tolerant.|https://treewalks.github.io//2022/12/16/incense_cedar_en.html|The name of this tree in the Konkow language, the Maidu Concow tribe\'s language, is hö\'-tä|Western North America (Oregon to Baja California)</item>
    <item>Peace Garden|Peace Garden features some california native / indigenous species|Besides the majestic trees and plants adjacent to the library building feel free to check out the memorials too.|https://treewalks.github.io//2022/12/17/peace_garden_en.html|You can find statues of Mahatma Gandhi, Nelson Mandela, César E. Chávez, Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr., and Jane Addams|</item>
    <item>Giant Sequoia|Evergreen. Native to the Sierra Nevada of California.|Evergreen. Native to the Sierra Nevada of California. Conical growth habit when young, becoming columnar. Bark is reddish brown, fire-resistant. Dense, gray-green, scalelike foliage. This specimen was planted in 1990. Just south of this tree on the other side of the walkway there’s a Coast Redwood (which is California native) and then another Giant Sequoia which is also very young but bigger than the walk’s tree.|https://treewalks.github.io//2022/12/18/giant_sequoia_en.html|Giant sequoias share the title of California state tree with the California redwood|Sierra Nevada of California</item>
    <item>Mediterranean Fan Palm|The only palm native to Europe. Drought tolerant.|Evergreen. Native to the Mediterranean region. The only palm native to Europe. Plant develops a clumping form from basal off-shoots. Light green, fan-shaped leaves. Drought tolerant. There are multiple groups of them along the East wall of the South Gym.|https://treewalks.github.io//2022/12/19/mediterranian_fan_palm_en.html|Husks of the Mediterranean fan palm contain high amounts of tannin, giving them use as an astringent|Mediterranean region</item>
    <item>Fruitless Olive|Evergreen. Native to the Mediterranean region. Drought tolerant.|Evergreen. Native to the Mediterranean region. Usually multi-trunked. Leathery, gray-green leaves. Small, fragrant, white flowers. Fruit is green when young, ripening to black before dropping. Drought tolerant.|https://treewalks.github.io//2022/12/20/fruitless_olives_en.html|Olive trees are longevous, with the oldest known individual being 3,350 years old, located in Abrantes, Portugal.|Mediterranean region</item>
    <item>California Black Oak|Deciduous. Native to the United States.|Deciduous. Native to the United States. Broadly conical with rounded crown when mature. Smooth, gray-brown bark. Glossy leaves have deeply cut and parted lobes. Yellow to red-brown fall color.|https://treewalks.github.io//2022/12/21/california_black_oak_en.html|California black oaks are an important food source and shelter for California animals; all 68 birds in the Tehachapi Mountains forage on this oak|United States</item>
    <item>California Redbud|Deciduous. Native to California, Utah, and Arizona.|Deciduous. Native to California, Utah, and Arizona. Found in foothills of the Sierra Nevada from 1,000’-4000’ in elevation. Usually multi-trunked. Stakeless clusters of pink to magenta flowers are borne along the branches and trunk during March and April. Fruit is a brown seed pod. Drought tolerant when established.|https://treewalks.github.io//2022/12/22/california_red_bud_en.html|Twigs from the western redbud are used in basket weaving by indigenous peoples and produce a faint reddish dye in the basket|California, Utah, Arizona</item>
    <item>Aleppo pine|Evergreen. Native to the Mediterranean region. Drought tolerant.|Evergreen. Native to the Mediterranean region. Open growth habit and rounded crown when mature. Short, light green needles in bundles of two. Drought tolerant.|https://treewalks.github.io//2022/12/23/aleppo_pine_en.html|Resin from Aleppo pines is used to flavor retsina, a traditional Greek white resinated wine|Mediterranean region</item>
    <item>White alder|Native to coastal areas, along stream banks, from British Columbia to California.|Deciduous. Native to coastal areas, along stream banks, from British Columbia to California. Coarsely toothed, dark green leaves have paler undersides. Flowers are greenish-yellow catkins. Fruit is a small, brown, woody cone.|https://treewalks.github.io//2022/12/24/white_alder_en.html|Alder trees can fix nitrogen on their own, allowing them to tolerate infertile soils|Coastal areas from British Columbia to California</item>
  </string-array>
</resources>
